Aaron M. Rowan, M.B.A. P.M.P. C.Q.E

14718 Plessis Place Huntersville, NC 28078 (315) 297 - 9648 / <u>a.rowan@alum.rpi.edu</u> PORTFOLIO: https://arowan-portfolio.azurewebsites.net/

Executive Summary: C# ASP.Net Full Stack Developer. More than 10 years of SQL Query Development and Data Analysis Experience. Extensive project management and team facilitation experience. Project management experience includes software, transactional process and manufacturing process development. Lean business system leadership experience. Real demonstrated skills to bring people together, share experience and solve the problems facing the business.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Masters of Business Admin	Languages:	Application Software:
- Certified Lean Black Belt	- HTML5	- Visual Studio
- Certified PM Professional	- CSS3 + Bootstrap	- SQL Server Mgmt. Studio
- Certified Quality Engineer	- JavaScript	- iPython / Jupyter
	- C #	- Azure Machine Learning Studio
<u>Platforms:</u>	- AngularJS	- Microsoft Office (EXCEL)
- Windows	- Python	- Minitab
- SQL Server, Oracle	- TSQL, PLSQL	- SAS JMP
- MVC	- FireBase	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Consulting Charlotte, NC August 2016 - Present

Senior Consultant

Diverse Software and Web Development Roles

- 630 Marketing Reworking Structured Data Demonstration Website (see Portfolio)
- BusDat.com Sales Consulting Marketing Analysis
- RusticJustice.co Collaborating Partner Developing Advanced Music Sharing App (AngularJS)
- Personal Training Coder Foundry Intensive Coding Bootcamp (Graduation September 2016)

Mecklenburg County Government

Charlotte, NC

February 2015 – July 2016

Senior Process Consultant

Focus on Quality and Throughput of Key Services

Accomplishments

- Used customer queue data to design new combined facility as part of 'Bringing Mecklenburg County to You' initiative.
- Identified and created a comprehensive court document tracking e-form to organize the work of over 70 caseworkers.

Novelis Inc. Oswego, NY October 2013 – October 2014

Quality Engineer

Owner of Roll Shop Quality System and Plant Quality Capital Projects

Accomplishments

- Developed a testing and calibration process to ensure accurate roughness testing results.
- Managed a \$750,000 program of 9 simultaneous projects to prepare for upcoming product launch.

Novelis Inc. Oswego, NY June 2011 – October 2013

Plant Energy Leader

Managed Procurement and Use of Electricity and Natural Gas Supply of Greater than \$30 Million Annually Accomplishments

- Developed an energy dashboard to provide daily energy usage and SPC trending.
- Facilitated \$1 million project to replace over 8,500 high-bay lighting fixtures.
- Sponsored a team to identify, organize, prioritize and execute energy reduction projects.
- Utilized a Monte Carlo Analysis to identify critical risk involving our natural gas supply.

Certified Lean-Six Sigma Black Belt

Identified, organized and facilitated more than 40 projects

Accomplishments

- Environmental Focus Projects reduced CO2 equivalent of 250,000 cars annually.
- Lead high-risk project to transport 8 million pounds of molten aluminum via truck from a key supplier.

Novelis Inc. Oswego, NY May 2003 – October 2006

Process Metallurgist – Aluminum Casting

Managed scrap blending, process analysis, and equipment calibration

<u>Accomplishments</u>

• Facilitated a team to develop a process that reduced inventory of our #1 product by 10%.

EDUCATION

Masters of Business Administration - State University of New York at Oswego

July 2013

• Focus on Project Management, Accounting and Management of Financial Institutions

Bachelors of Science Materials Engineering – Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

May 2003

- Undergraduate Research: Nano-particle ZnO electrical surge suppression characteristics
- Language: German Fluent (Studied 1 year at the ETH Zurich, Einstein's Alma Mater)

CERTIFICATIONS & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- PMI PMP Certification #1882405
- ASQ CQE Certification #62457
- ISO 9001: TS16949 Certified Auditor
- Professional Training: 7 Habits of Highly Effective People (Franklin-Covey), Dale Carnegie

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- Trustee at St. Joseph's Church Oswego
- Founding executive board member of 'Cans for The Community'
- Lead mentor engineer for FIRST Robotics Oswego County